Finding aid for the Getty Center for Education in the Arts, Stephen M. Dobbs records, 1984-1989, undated (bulk 1987-1989) IA20027
Institutional Records and Archives
- Chronological correspondence, 1987-1989; Series I.; 75 Linear Feet 15 boxes
  - December 8, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-14, Folder 11)
  - December 7, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-14, Folder 12)
  - December 3-4, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-14, Folder 13)
  - December 1-2, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-14, Folder 14)
  - November 25-30, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-14, Folder 15)
  - November 24, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-14, Folder 16)
  - November 20-23, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-14, Folder 17)
  - November 19, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-14, Folder 18)
  - November 18, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-14, Folder 19)
  - November 16-17, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-14, Folder 20)
  - November 12-15, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 1)
  - November 11, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 2)
  - November 10, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 3)
  - November 7-9, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 4)
  - November 6, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 5)
  - November 4-5, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 6)
  - November 2-3, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 7)
  - October 29-30, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 8)
  - October 23-27, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 9)
  - October 19-22, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 10)
  - October 17, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 11)
  - October 16, 1987, [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 12-13)
  - October 13-14, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 14)
  - October 12, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 15)
  - October 8-10, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 16)
  - October 2-7, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 17)
  - October 1, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 18)
  - September 29-30, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 19)
  - September 23-28, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 20)
  - September 2-21, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-15, Folder 21)
- Subject correspondence, 1984-1989; Series II.; 45 Linear Feet 9 boxes
  These records are arranged in alphabetical order by subject. Within each subject, the records are within reverse chronological order.
  Records comprise correspondence, memoranda, drafts, reports, notes, resumes, agenda, printed materials, financial documents, iteneraries, and speeches, dating 1987-1989, created and maintained by Stephen Dobbs, Senior Program Officer for the Getty Center for Education in the Arts. The majority of the records consist of correspondence and memoranda, with relevant attachments. External correspondence was often directed toward art educators and organzations. Internal correspondence and memoranda were directed toward GCAE staff, particularly Lani Duke, the Program Head. The records include drafts of, and comments on, a policy paper on perceptions of discipline-based arts education and the Getty Center; advisory committees correspondence; budget planning; staff retreats; children's television; translations of DBAE materials into Chinese; general announcements about developments elsewhere in the Getty; work with a public relations firm to advertise DBAE; regional art education institutes; grants of art related special initaitives; and the traveling and speeches Dobbs delivered to discuss art education theories.
  - Advocacy
    - Miscellaneous, June 1986-February 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-16, Folder 1)
    - Perceptions, drafts, September 1987-July 1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-16, Folder 2-3)
    - Perceptions, miscellaneous, June 1987-December 1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-16, Folder 4-5)
    - Perceptions, reviews, December 1987-April 1988; [3 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-16, Folder 6-8)
    - Press contacts, February-March 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-16, Folder 9)
  - Center Internal Affairs
    - Advisory Committee, February 1987-November 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-16, Folder 10)
    - Budget process, February 1987-November 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-16, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, May 1987-May 1989; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-17, Folder 1-2)
    - Program Officer (includes resumes), August 1987-April 1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-17, Folder 3-4)
    - Responses to critics, April-May 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-17, Folder 5)
    - Staff retreats, December 1987-June 1989; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-17, Folder 6-7)
    - Visitors, March 1988-March 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-17, Folder 8)
  - Center Programs
    - Advocacy, March 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-17, Folder 9)
    - Children's television, July 1987-March 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-17, Folder 10-11)
    - Curriculum Development Institute, July 1988-March 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-17, Folder 12)
  - China
    - Translations, 1988; [3 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-17, Folder 13-15)
  - Conferences and Seminars
    - Asian Pacific Conference on Arts Education, March-August 1989; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-17, Folder 16-17)
    - Miscellaneous, April-August 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-17, Folder 18)
    - University of Maryland, February-August 1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-18, Folder 1-2)
  - Discipline-Based Arts Education Theory
    - Correspondence, April-December 1987; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-18, Folder 3-4)
    - Critics, June 1987-December 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-18, Folder 5)
    - General, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-18, Folder 6)
    - Issues seminar, 1989; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-18, Folder 7-8)
    - Publications, March 1987-October 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-18, Folder 9)
  - District Grants
    - Bartholomew, October 1987-March 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-18, Folder 10)
    - Eugene, March-June 1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-18, Folder 11-12)
    - Multi-year study, January 1987-March 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-18, Folder 13)
    - Portland, April-December 1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-18, Folder 14-15)
    - Provo, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 1)
    - Robbinsdale, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 2)
  - Federal
    - Miscellaneous, August 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 3)
  - Getty Trust Programs
    - Art History Information Program, April 1988-March 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 4)
    - Building Program, May 1987-January 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 5)
    - Center for the History of Art and the Humanities, February-July 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 6)
    - Conservation Institute, April-December 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 7)
    - Grant Program, April 1988-August 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 8)
    - J. Paul Getty Museum/Miscellaneous, September 1987-May 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 9)
    - J. Paul Getty Museum/Press, 1984-1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 10-11)
    - Program for Art on Film, September 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 12)
  - Inquiries
    - Assessment, April 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 13)
    - Curriculum Development, October 1987-December 1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 14-15)
    - Discipline Based Art-Education Theory, January-October 1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 16-17)
    - Grants, November 1987-October 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous, September 1987-August 1989; [3 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-19, Folder 19-21)
    - Staff Development, August 1987-October 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-20, Folder 1)
  - National Art Education Association
    - Art Education Journal, May 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-20, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-20, Folder 3)
    - Discipline Based Art-Education Anthology, August 1986-June 1989; [3 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-20, Folder 4-6)
    - Los Angeles Conference, October 1987-April 1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-20, Folder 7-8)
    - Mini-Institute/Los Angeles, July 1987-July 1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-20, Folder 9-10)
    - Miscellaneous, July 1987-January 1989; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-20, Folder 11-12)
    - Publications, 1988-1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-20, Folder 13)
    - Washington D.C. Conference, 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-20, Folder 14)
  - Ogilvy and Mather
    - Meetings, 1988-1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-20, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1987-1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-20, Folder 16)
    - Monthly reports, August 1987-February 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-21, Folder 1)
    - Proposals, 1987-1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-21, Folder 2)
    - PTA Project, 1985-1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-21, Folder 3-4)
    - Center Newsletter, August 1987-May 1989; [4 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-21, Folder 5-8)
  - Publications
    - Complimentary, January-April 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-21, Folder 9)
    - Information Brochure, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-21, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, June 1987-May 1989; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-21, Folder 11-12)
  - Regional Institutes
    - Arizona, April 1987-October 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-21, Folder 13)
    - Florida, 1987-1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-21, Folder 14)
    - Grant panel reviews, December 1986-June 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-22, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, October 1988-April 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-22, Folder 2)
    - Minnesota, May 1987-October 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-22, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, May 1987-November 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-22, Folder 4)
    - Multi-Year Study, November 1987-March 1989; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-22, Folder 5-6)
    - Nebraska, October 1987-December 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-22, Folder 7)
    - Ohio, October 1987-March 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-22, Folder 8)
    - Pennslyvania, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-22, Folder 9)
    - Rhode Island, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-22, Folder 10)
    - Texas, May 1987-April 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-22, Folder 11)
  - Roundtables
    - Milwaukee, April 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-22, Folder 12)
    - Philadelphia, November 1987-March 1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-22, Folder 13-14)
    - Tulsa, December 1987-October 1988; [folder 1 of 2] (Box 2005.IA.14-22, Folder 15)
    - Tulsa, December 1987-October 1988; [folder 2 of 2] (Box 2005.IA.14-23, Folder 1)
  - Special Initiative Grants
    - Grisby, Eugene, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-23, Folder 2)
    - Hausman, Jerry, 1987; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-23, Folder 3-4)
    - Kaagen, Steve, June 1987-March 1989; [4 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-23, Folder 5-8)
    - Marante, Ken, May 1987-March 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-23, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, October 1987-July 1989; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-23, Folder 10-11)
    - Schultz, Larry, February-August 1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 1-2)
    - Wurman, Richard, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 3)
  - Travel
    - Arizona/Tuscon, October 1987-1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 4)
    - Arizona/Wickenburg, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 5)
    - California/Arcata, July 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 6)
    - California/Fresno, October 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 7)
    - California/Merced, June 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 8)
    - California/San Deigo, 1987-1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 9-10)
    - California/San Francisco, 1987-1988; [2 folders] (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 11-12)
    - East Coast, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 13)
    - Florida/Daytona Beach, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 14)
    - Illinois/Chicago, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 15)
    - Indiana/Bloomington, November 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 16)
    - Indiana/Indianapolis, 1987 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 17)
    - Indiana/South Bend, 1989 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 18)
    - Invitations declined, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 19)
    - Louisiana/New Orleans, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 21)
    - New Jersey/New Brunswick, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 22)
    - Oregon/Portland, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 23)
    - Virginia/Roanoke, 1988 (Box 2005.IA.14-24, Folder 24)